Professor Oobleck?
Oobleck教授？
Yes, I'm afraid those bags won't be necessary, girls
是啊，恐怕那些包包不用帶了，女士們
Seeing as you've opted to shadow a Huntsman on what is now essentially a reconnaissance mission
由於你們在一個不折不扣的偵察任務裡選擇跟隨獵人
I can assure you, we will not be establishing a single base of operations
我可以保證，我們不會建立任何據點
Rather, we will be traversing several miles of hazardous wasteland
而是要橫穿幾英里危險的廢墟
and making camp in any defendable locations we may stumble upon
然後在某個可能會撞見的易守難攻處紮營
I packed all of our essentials myself, plotted our air course, and readied the airship, and..
我親自打包了所有必需品，制定了航線，準備了飛船，以及..
It's Doctor Oobleck
我是Oobleck博士
I didn't earn the Ph.D. for fun, thank you very much!
我拿博士學位不是為了玩，多謝！
Uhhh..
呃..
Come now, children, according to my schedule, we are already three minutes behind..
快來吧孩子們，根據我的計劃我們已經遲到三分鐘了..
Schedule!
計劃！
Well, alright then..
那好吧..
Looks like we're going to save the world with Doctor Oobleck-
看來我們要跟Oobleck博士拯救世界-
Okay yeah when you say it out loud, it sounds worse
好吧，大聲說這句話感覺更羞恥
Save the world?
拯救世界？
You're going on world-saving missions without us?
你們做拯救世界的任務卻不帶我們？
I'm hurt, sad!
我傷了，桑心！
Maybe a little hungry?
可能還有點餓？
That last one's not your fault, though
不過最後那條不怪你們
Ren..
Ren..
Sounds exciting, where you going?
貌似很棒，你們去哪兒？
Oh, just outside the kingdom..
噢，只是王國外邊..
Hey! So are we!
嘿！我們也是！
Ren and Nora wanted to shadow the sheriff of a nearby village
Ren和Nora想跟隨一個附近村莊的治安官
We set out tomorrow
我們明天出發
Then you can party with us tonight!
那你們今晚可以跟我們開派對！
We're shadowing a crime specialist, all inner-city detective stuff
我們要跟隨一名破案專家，所有市中心的偵探活
We get junior badges
能拿初級徽章
We normally go to the city with you guys, which means stuff's always exploding and junk
我們一般跟你們進城，就意味著面臨各種爆炸和報廢
So we thought this might be a better way to check out the kingdom when it's, you know..normal
所以咱們覺得趁情況還正常時查看一下王國..更好
Well..
這..
Four minutes, ladies!
四分鐘了，女士們！
Well, uh..
好吧，那..
Wish us luck
祝我們好運
I guess I just never saw you as much of a fighter
我好像從未見過你戰鬥
I admit I fancy myself more of an..intellectual
我承認我把自己設定得更偏..知識分子
But I can assure you, as a Huntsman, I've had my fair share of tussles
但我保證，作為一個獵人，我也有過自己的格鬥經歷
Like the mushroom?
那種蘑菇？
Those are truffles
那些是松露
Like the sprout?
那種球芽？
Those are Brussels
那些是甘藍
Besides
再說
Given my expertise in the field of history as well as my dabblings in the archaeological surveys
由於我擁有歷史領域的專業知識，及對考古調查方面的涉獵
Our dear headmaster saw fit to assign me to this particular..
親愛的校長覺得我適合來執行這個特別的..
Assignment
任務
What does history have to do with this?
這任務跟歷史有什麼關係？
Why, what a preposterous question, you silly girl!
哇，這問題真荒謬，傻丫頭！
Why, history is the backbone of our very society!
歷史可是我們社會的脊樑骨啊！
And the liver!
以及肝臟！
Probably the kidneys, if I were to wager
說不定還是腎，要我賭的話
And that means..
就是說..
The southeast quadrant outside of Vale is home to wild forests and deep caves
溪谷外的東南區域是大片的原始森林和幽深的洞穴
But, it is also the location to one of the kingdom's greatest failures
不過，那地方也擁有王國最失敗的黑歷史之一
Mountain Glenn
幽谷山脈
That's right, it was an expansion of Vale
沒錯，溪谷曾擴張到那裡
But in the end it was overrun by Grimm and fenced off from the rest of the city
但最後卻被戮獸佔據，與溪谷其他地區隔離了
Correct! And now it stands abandoned as a dark reminder
正解！現在被遺棄著，提醒著黑暗的存在
And a likely place for a hideout
有可能被當成藏身之處
Precisely
完全正確
Ladies, you still may be students
女士們，或許你們還是學生
But as of this moment, your first mission as a Huntress has begun
但這一刻，你作為獵人的第一項任務已經開始了
From this point forward, you need to do exactly as I say
從現在起，你們要嚴格按我說的做
Do you understand?
明白了嗎？
Ruby!
Ruby！
I thought I told you to leave all of your bags back at school
我不是告訴過你把包都留在學校嗎？
But, uh..you hadn't told us to listen to you yet
不過..你當時並沒讓我們嚴格聽從你
So I didn't
所以我沒聽
She's not wrong..
說得好有道理..
Very well, Ruby, leave your bag here, we can pick it up upon our return
好吧Ruby，把包留在這裡，我們可以回來時再拿
But I, well..
但我，呃..
Young lady, what in the world could you possibly have in that bag that could be so important to bring it with..
小姐，那個包裡到底有什麼貴重之物能讓你一直帶著..
Get back in the bag..
給我鑽回去..
We're here to investigate an abandoned urban jungle teeming with death and hostility
我們來這裡調查這個充滿死亡敵對氣息的廢棄都市叢林
And you brought..
而你帶了..
A dog..
一隻汪星人..
I, uhh..
我，呃..
Genius!
天才！
Canines are historically known for their perceptive nose and heightened sense of sound
犬類自古以來就以靈敏的嗅覺和聽覺著稱
making them excellent companions for hunts such as ours!
是我們這種搜索任務的最佳夥伴
I'm a genius
我就是天才
So, what're your orders, Doctor?
那麼你的指示是什麼，博士？
Ah yes, straight to the chase, I like it
很好，直奔主題，我喜歡
As you've been informed, the southeast area has been marked as a recent hotspot for Grimm activity
如你們所知，最近東南方這邊的戮獸活動非常活躍
Now, there are several possible explanations for this behavior, one of which being..
對於這種現象有幾種可能的解釋，其中一種就是..
Grimm
戮獸
Uh, what?
呃，啥？
A creature of Grimm approximately one hundred yards from us at this very moment
此時此刻就有一隻戮獸離我們大約百碼開外
What?!
什麼！？
Stop!
住手！
Huh?
哈？
There're a number of reasons why Grimm will congregate in this particular area
戮獸在這個特定的地方聚集有幾種原因
The most likely of which will be their attraction to negativity
其中最有可能的就是它們被負能量吸引
Sadness
悲傷
Envy
嫉妒
Loneliness
孤獨
Hatred
憎恨
All qualities that are likely held by our hidden group harboring ill intent
很可能都是藏在這裡圖謀不軌的傢伙們散發的
So..what now?
那..現在呢？
We wait
等待時機
We track
然後追蹤
If this specimen leads us to its pack, that pack may subsequently lead us to our prey
若這只帶我們找到它的群落，群落就可能帶我們找到獵物
How long do we wait?
我們要等多久？
It's uncertain, hours, days, weeks
不確定，幾小時，幾天，幾周
Why, lone Grimm have been known to stay isolated from the pack for months
畢竟落單的戮獸一般幾個月都不回群
and there's the whole pack
而那就是整群了
What?
神馬？
And now they've seen us
我們被發現了
What?!
吶尼！？
And now they've seen us!
我們被發現了！
I take it tracking is out of the question?
我能認為追蹤不再可行麼？
An accurate assumption, yes
推理正確，沒錯
What's the plan, then?
那現在怎麼辦？
Show me what you're capable of
讓我看看你們的本事
Cover your ears, Zwei~
摀住耳朵，Zwei~
Heh, piece of cake
呵，小菜一碟
Do not celebrate yet
別高興太早
For I am certain this is the first bout of many
我確定這只是一大波的第一波
Shall we continue?
我們繼續吧？
Excellent work, girls!
幹得漂亮，姑娘們！
Fortunately, there doesn't seem to be any signs of criminal operations in this sector
幸好這片區域看上去沒有任何犯罪活動的跡象
Oh, well, moving on!
好吧，繼續前進！
Hey, Doc, you know, I was actually looking forward to seeing a pro Huntsman in action
嘿，博士，要知道我可是很期待見識職業獵人的手段
Like, fighting, or at least helping us fight?
比如戰鬥，或至少加個Buff嘛？
Oh, but I am in action
哦，但我正是在行動
Scouring the ruins of this once great city for any signs of irregularity
調查這座曾經輝煌的城市廢墟中任何不尋常的蛛絲馬跡
Not every mission is filled with daring and heroism, girls
不是每個任務都充滿著膽量比拚和英雄主義，姑娘們
Sometimes it's just a heightened form of extermination
有時只是個高級形式的殲滅任務
Remember, this is a job
要記住，這是個工作
And you all signed up for it
你們都是自願選的
I do hope you understand that
希望你們能明白
Well, yeah..
呃，對..
Of course
當然明白
Hmm..
哼..
Tell me, Yang
告訴我，Yang
Why did you choose this line of work?
你為何要選這個職業？
Huh?
哈？
Well, to fight monsters and save..
呃，為了打怪獸，拯救..
No, that is what you do, I want to know why you do it
不，這是你的工作內容，我想知道你的動機
The honest reason as to why you want to be a Huntress
你想成為獵人的真實原因
The honest reason?
真實原因？
I'm a thrill-seeker
我是個尋求刺激的人
I wanna travel around the world and get wrapped up in as many crazy adventures as I can
我想環遊世界，並盡力置身於一堆瘋狂的冒險中
And if I help people along the way, then that's even better
而且若能在旅途中幫助他人，那就更好了
It's a win-win, you know?
這是雙贏嘛，對吧？
I see
懂了
And you, Miss Schnee?
你呢，Schnee小姐？
A girl born into fame and fortune such as yourself certainly doesn't need the extra work
像你這種名門貴族出生的大小姐完全不需要額外工作嘛
So..
所以..
Why choose this, over a cushy job in Atlas?
為何選這個，而不在阿特拉斯找個輕鬆的活呢？
It's exactly as you said
正如你所言
I'm a Schnee, I have a legacy of honor to uphold
我是雪倪家族的，要守護傳承的榮耀
Once I realized I was capable of fighting
當我意識到自己可以戰鬥
There was no longer a question of what I would do with my life
我就對此生的未來不再迷茫了
It was my duty
這是我的義務
Interesting
有意思
And what about you, Blake?
你又如何呢，Blake？
You seem to carry yourself with a sense of purpose
你看起來抱著明確的目標
There's too much wrong in this world to just stand by and do nothing
這個世界太多錯誤讓人無法袖手旁觀
Inequality, corruption, someone has to stop it
不平等，腐敗，必須有人去阻止
Very well
非常好
How?
怎麼做？
I, Uh..
我，呃..
Hmm..
唔..
Sorry, uhh..are we ready to keep going?
抱歉，準備好繼續前進了嗎？
No! I believe that will have to do for today
不，我想今天已經夠了
It's going to be dark soon
馬上就要天黑了
You three, set up camp in that building
你們三個，在那棟樓裡紮營
Oh, and please do make sure that there are no more of those..
哦，還請確保那裡不再有這些..
creatures
生物了
Your leader and I are going to secure the perimeter
我和你們隊長去確保周邊安全
Come, Ruby
來吧，Ruby
WOW
哇噢
What is that? It was awesome!
那是啥！？太厲害了！
That, my dear girl, is a Grimm
那是一種戮獸，乖女孩
Let's kill it
滅掉吧
I'm afraid your sniper rifle will do nothing more than agitate a Grimm of that size
恐怕你的狙擊步槍最多只能激怒這種體型的戮獸吧
But..what if it attacks us?
可是..它們攻擊我們怎麼辦？
Fret not, Ruby, those Goliaths are not concerned with us
別擔心Ruby，這些歌利亞巨象根本不鳥我們
Ruby, not every Grimm is mindless
Ruby，不是所有戮獸都沒思想
or rather not every Grimm is still mindless
或者說不是所有戮獸至今還沒思想
You see, the Grimm you see before you are so powerful
要知道，你眼前的戮獸非常強大
so superior to the Grimm you fought
比你之前打的那些高級多了
that they've undoubtedly lived hundreds of years
毫無疑問它們已經活了幾百年了
And in that time between killing humans and attacking our borders, they've done one important thing
幾百年裡除了攻擊我們的邊境、殘殺人類，它們還做了一件重要的事
They've learned
學習
They've learned that when they attack our borders, they're likely to die
它們學到了當攻擊我們的邊境時，可能會被殺
and what we lack in strength, we make up for in will
學到了我們力量中缺乏的部分會用意志彌補
and that killing one human will only bring more
學到了殺死一個人類只會招來更多
Then..
那..
Why are they still so close to the city?
為什麼它們依然如此靠近城市？
What are they doing?
它們在幹什麼？
Waiting
等待
Doctor Oobleck?
Oobleck博士？
Hmm?
嗯？
I was wondering..
我在好奇..
Wondering why I've been interrogating your teammates all day?
好奇我為什麼整天都在詢問你的隊友？
Actually..
其實..
I was wondering..
我在好奇..
Why did you want to become a Huntsman?
你為什麼要成為獵人？
Look around and tell me what you see
環顧四周，告訴我你看到了什麼
Lots of old buildings
一堆舊建築物
Uh, empty streets..
呃，空蕩蕩的街道
I see lives that could have been saved
我看到的是本來可以挽救的生命
As a Huntsman, it is my job to protect the people
作為獵人，保護大家是我的職責
And although I'm capable of doing it with traditional weaponry
雖然我能用傳統的兵器來履行職責
I believe I can make a much larger impact if I do it with my mind
我相信如果用上頭腦，我可以產生大得多的影響
As a teacher, I'm able to take knowledge, the most powerful weapon of them all
作為教師，我能運用知識這個最強有力的武器
and place it in the hands of every student that passes through my classroom
並把它傳遞到每個我課堂上的學生手裡
I look at this wasteland, and I see lives that could have been saved
我看著這片廢墟，看到了本可拯救的生命
But I also see an opportunity
但我也看到了機會
An opportunity to study these ruins and learn from this tragedy
一個機會來研究這片廢墟、吸取悲劇的教訓
And therefore become stronger
從而變得更堅強
I am a Huntsman, Ruby
我是個獵人，Ruby
Because there is nothing else in this world..
因為這世上沒有其他職業..
I would rather be
更讓我想做了
I can't believe we didn't find anything
不敢相信我們什麼都沒發現
We've always been fortunate enough to be in the right place at the right time
我們總是幸運地在合適的時機出現在正確的地點
I guess we can't always have luck on our side
我想運氣不會一直站在我們這邊
That's not what I meant
我不是那個意思
Huh?
哈？
Earlier, about..upholding the legacy
之前，那些..守護傳承什麼的
There's more to it than that
不是那麼簡單
Yeah..
是啊..
No, me too, I mean..
我也是，我是說..
I don't know
不知道
I don't know, either
我也不知道
I know what I want to do, but..
我知道我想做什麼，但..
I figured I'd always take things one step at a time
我發現我做事應該保持一步一個腳印
Well, it doesn't matter
嘛，沒關係的
We know why we're here, right?
我們知道來這裡的目的，對吧
Ah, wonderful, a textbook campfire!
啊，好贊，教課書般標準的篝火！
Ah, fire!
啊，火啊！
So..warm..
好..暖..
Very good, eat your dinners and hurry to bed
非常好，快吃飯，早點睡
We have a lot of ground to cover tomorrow
我們明天還有很多路要走
and we'll need you to take turns keeping watch over our temporary abode
而且還需要你們輪流守夜保護這個臨時住處
Any volunteers for first watch?
誰自願守第一輪？
Yo
這裡
Hey, did Oobleck ask you why you wanted to be a Huntress?
嘿，Oobleck有問你當獵人的理由了嗎？
I mean..what did you tell him?
我是說..你怎麼回答的？
Hmm..no, he didn't, weird
嗯..他沒問，奇怪
Oh well, good night, guys
就這樣，晚安吧夥伴們
Don't worry
別擔心
Things will be better tomorrow
明天情況會好的
BRB
BRB
This SUB is presented by Baidu RWBY Bar Creator: sbz_kid
本字幕由百度RWBY吧提供 片源/翻譯/時間軸/特效/後期：sbz_kid